Call.
>> Roll call. Katie Ames.
Absent.
Chad Halvorson.
Absent. Excused.
Rob Graham.
>> Present.
>> Ryan Whitehead.
>> Ken Duggas.
>> Present.
>> Chair, we have a quorum.
>> Thank you. Do we have any disclosures
that need to be made amongst the board?
>> Oop.
>> All right.
Hearing none, I will move to item number
four, election of officers.
>> Chair, if you could hold on for 1 second
real quick. I need to double check the
link.
Um Katie is trying to get on right now,
so I will Great. Double check that. Hold
on 1 sec.
>> So, acting chair looks like our chair
will be on momentarily.
And uh just for the record, we cannot
nominate
um Chad as every position, but we could
try.
I actually don't recall who holds the
secretary and treasurer positions right
now.
>> Katie is on Zoom now.
Hi guys.
>> Perfect. Thank you, Katie. Uh
>> I'm sorry. I had the wrong link.
>> That's all right. We have That's
completely my fault. I have to take the
blame on that cuz I sent the invite. Um
but we've already called the meeting to
order, so we're still uh we're right at
the beginning of the
um election of officers.
>> Great. Okay.
>> All right. Um, I can walk you all
through this if you like for the
election of officers. Annually we're uh
we're required to
um appoint officers for 1-year period
per our bylaws. Um, the positions we
have up up this year are a president,
vice president, secretary, and
treasurer. Um, I would like to note that
the secretary and treasurer positions
are more honorary.
Uh they don't really have any tasks. Uh
our treasurer services are being
conducted through our city treasurer's
office.
Um, and we're continuing to provide
reports on on that as the finances come
in.
So, with that um the first item would be
nominations for president. What I would
when nominating a a president, whoever
does that, I would ask that they
um ask that person if they do desire to
hold that role.
So, I'll hand it back over to Katie.
Thank you.
>> Thank you. Um, well, I think we could
make it easy and just throw everybody
under the bus. Then, if you're all
willing to take on the same roles that
you've had before, Charles, can we do it
that way?
>> Chair, if you would, you can
um
uh basically approve a slate if you'd
like to do that. Um, we'll just clarify
what that slate looks like. We were
just discussing who's secretary and
who's treasurer, and
we don't have the records immediately in
front of us, but we can clarify that and
up to her about looking it up.
>> Okay.
Um, well, I know that I'm president,
Rob's vice president. I can't remember
who's secretary and treasurer are,
either.
But, I would be happy to do that again.
Is anyone opposed to taking on their
their same role or continuing their
role?
>> Madam Chair, this is Ryan. I I if I was
treasurer before, I would be okay with
that again. So.
>> I think you were. That that seems to
make sense to me.
>> That's what I recall, but I just was
looking for a clarification. I'm fine
with to designate that position.
>> Charles, I don't know if I can nominate
a slate or if someone else has to do
that.
>> Madam Chair,
Ken Duggan.
I will I will
nominate our existing officers
to another or an additional term.
And that would be you as president, Rob
as vice president, Chad as secretary,
and Ryan as treasurer.
>> I'll second that.
>> Okay, all those in favor say I.
>> I.
>> Okay, motion passes. That was easy.
>> Thank you.
Um the next item is approval of the
minutes, and I was a little
little zealous when I put the meeting
agenda together, and I thought I would
have the minutes complete by then, but I
did not. So, I would ask that we just
move past the minutes. We postpone that
to the next meeting, and we'll get those
complete.
>> I don't think we need to vote on that,
right? We can just postpone it.
>> It'd be nice to have a motion just to
postpone the minutes.
>> Madam Chair, this is Ryan. I'll make a
motion to postpone the minutes for
review to the next meeting.
>> This is Ken. I'll second.
>> All those in favor say I.
>> I.
>> Okay,
postpone that to the next meeting.
>> All right.
Thank you.
All right.
The next item will be the city-wide
blight designation discussion. I will go
ahead and and walk through this really
quick.
Um for
those of you that are have a device
online, we have this online, so I don't
know if you're able to follow through
with this. Um,
this was created as uh, basically
uh, consolidation of some of the
existing documents we have, removal of
different elements that
were no longer relevant. Um, and not all
plans and projects were included, um, or
blight designations were included in the
study from the past. We really just
wanted to try to highlight different
areas of the community, um, and just
show how it exists as a general
condition.
Um, at our last meeting we had back in
September, we did uh, mention that many
communities have taken different
approaches as to how blight studies are
done. Laramie uh, had done a citywide
blight designation highlighting three
smaller areas of blight in their
community to expand to the entirety of
the community.
Douglas is working um, on a blight
designation for their entire community
as well. Um, they are still um,
looking to have one that expands when
the city annexes and expands.
Um, I have a meeting with JD Cox, their
city manager, on Friday. We're going to
discuss what we've recently learned
about how that works. Long story short
is it is problematic in the state of
Wyoming, um, without concurrence from
the county commissioners to have the
blight study move, um, as the city
annexes. So, uh, the way this has been
prepared is it would require amendments
that would still have to occur, um, as
we annex lands. And those can be looked
at either annually or they could be
looked at as specific projects go in.
Um, that would be something we will have
to to deal with and address as those
annexations occur.
Now, one of the unique things I would
like to note about, um, adding
additional areas as blight in the
in the plan.
You do not necessarily need to prove
existing conditions of blight exist in
that blight area.
The way the state statutes are written
is it also has a caveat that it could
prevent the
the addition or the increase of slum or
blight conditions. So, for example, if
there's an area that is annexed that may
have
insufficient infrastructure or potential
for bad development characteristics,
that could qualify you know, for blight
and it would help alleviate nearby
blight and it could be added in. So,
there are avenues to bring in raw land
that is for all purposes flat and
undevelopable.
Um or flat and developable.
Um again, I just would like to note with
blight designation, this is just step
one. This opens the toolbox.
Every
property owner that wishes to use the
urban renewal tools would still have to
go through a plan and project process
where they
um identify what their intentions are
for their project and then they also
would go through a tax increment
financing application to prove that a
financial gap exists um that does uh
hinder or prohibit development and that
they are seeking a reasonable return.
Or they would be getting a reasonable
return on investment.
So, this is what we did. Uh we put
together the document and we have study
areas. We have 11 of them throughout the
community. Uh this is an overall
vicinity map just sort of indicating
where we where we looked. Um as you can
see, we've uh basically embraced a lot
of the earlier ones that are in the
downtown area.
Uh we have added new ones, which is area
number six which is the East Lincoln Way
uh or sorry, number six which is a
that reflects the recently approved
South Holiday Blight Study. We've added
number nine, which is the new East
Lincoln Way um Blight Designation, where
we looked for characteristics of blight
out there.
Um number 11 is an addition, which is
the area of South Cheyenne, which is
south of the railroad tracks, just to
the existing city limits out there. Uh
number 10 is Swan Ranch. Uh we added
that, and then we did focus on um some
other areas of North, including the uh
Dell Range District. Um and also the
Yellowstone uh District. So, those are
all newer areas. If you recall during
our September discussion, we had a lot
of discussion about where should that
western boundary be if we were to do
individual pockets, and we kept creeping
to the west, so those are sort of uh
detailing what has gone on in that area.
Um these next slides um all in intending
to do is just sort of uh just speak to
the uh blight conditions um that do
exist
um and how they're detailed. I don't
have too many words on the the
PowerPoints here.
But, this is looking at the um existing
the existing uh blight area in the Reed
Road Corridor.
Most of the previously found blight
items still exist today. So, what we
have done is we've actually recycled the
pictures, and we've recycled the blight
surveys
uh from the previous documents. Uh we
did do verification to identify if these
um conditions still um existed,
which they they did.
And the way this is framed is this would
say number one, this is number three,
four, five, six, and nine.
Is they're actually referring to this
blight conditions table that we put
together, which this, for example, is a
illustration
um of the finding of the condition that
there's deteriorated deteriorated or
deteriorating structures.
Um you look at number three, uh this is
uh faulty lot layout in relation to size
uh accessibility or usefulness. These
are weirdly shaped parcels that present
problems for development. So, we've uh
um
looped all of these together um in the
map and they've
we've highlighted them on the
uh in the document where we've put a
um verbage that supports each and every
one of these items.
West 15th Street, this is another one
that was uh approved um right at the
beginning of our urban renewal
activities.
Um this again um found several uh blight
uh conditions in the area. A lot of it
continues to haunt us today and is in
regard to poor platting um and confusion
on title. Uh just recently we were made
aware that there are a lot of concerns
with what is believed to be an alley uh
located between House Avenue um and
running between West Lincoln Way and
15th Street um all the way out to um
Oh, sorry. No, this is the wrong one.
That's the other expanded downtown. This
is West 15th. Uh West 15th still does
have a lot of issues with platting.
Um there are some deteriorating public
improvements in that area. Um as most of
you all are aware, there used to be a
rail line that ran through this area and
at one time the rail line was abandoned
and pieces of property, as illustrated
in item number six, uh those were uh
sold off to neighboring properties,
which has resulted in uh some isolated
lots in different areas.
So, this area continues to
uh show conditions of blight.
Heinz in the Hole, uh, this is another
one of the original projects. Uh, the
conditions there, the physical ones, uh,
remain the same as they did um, back
when this was first approved. Um,
everyone is optimistic that this will
hopefully be able to be redeveloped in
the near future. Uh, we're we're hoping
that this hole and the neighboring Heinz
building uh, will be able to be joined
together for a new development. So, I I
believe we're right on the edge of of
good there.
Again, this is showing three examples of
of the blight conditions being being
met.
Region Holland, uh, this is one that we
had a blight designation that was, uh,
assembled. Uh, this was primarily to
help, uh, deal with infrastructure um,
extensions and some um, other issues in
the area. Uh, since the time of
approval, some of the conditions of
blight have been been remediated. For
example, there was a
decaying abandoned structure on that
large property in the middle that has
been demolished, um, and that is no
longer there. And that was demolished
due to a a fire and an unsafe condition
that was on the property.
Still, there are items that exist in
this area, um, including, uh, roadways
that aren't, um, built to city
standards, uh,
decaying infrastructure, infrastructure
needing repair, or drainage, um, and
other unsanitary and unsafe conditions,
specifically regarding, uh, how storm
water is handled on some of these sites
because of the incomplete system out
that direction.
Expanded Downtown, I accidentally gave
you a little bit of a preview on this.
Um, this is one where there are numerous
conditions, um, that meets this
criteria. Again, you're seeing a number
three
uh which are two examples here of faulty
uh lot layout and uh
those uh lot layouts and and
such really limit its usefulness.
Um I was noting that off of House
Avenue, there is an alley between 15th
and
uh West Lincoln Way that runs to the
east and west. It goes behind uh the
green the former Green Door uh behind
Village Inn of Alhambra.
Um that's recently come to our attention
that it it may have not been properly
vacated. So, there's been a lot of
discussion on, "Well, what really
happened back in the late 1800s and the
early 1900s there?" Those are uh
conditions that exist um due to the fact
that those are old plats and the way
things were subdivided in the past that
they just were done differently back
then and they're hindering development
um at this time.
South Alhambra, this is the most recent
blight designation we had. Uh this was
initially one to help facilitate
redevelopment of uh property which is
developed as a parking lot at the
southwest corner of Holiday Park. Um but
after discussions with the Urban Renewal
Authority and staff, it was determined
that we were to expand this to a larger
area. So, we're still recognizing um
what was previously approved.
Again, it still's maintaining those uh
conditions of blight.
Liddel Range District, this is a new one
that um we have added and we did a
blight uh
um conditions survey on this area uh
right at the end of December. Um and it
was actually
if you start looking for blight and
signs of urban decay and and issues in
this area, it kind of is eye-opening
when you start looking around. Um we do
have a lot of vacant structures. Not all
of these are are pictured here, but for
example, you have the vacant IHOP, which
is there. We have the
uh building spaces next to Hobby Lobby,
which have been vacant for excessive
periods of time. We have a lot of
vacancies in the shopping mall and those
types of items. Um in addition, there is
a lot of uh decaying infrastructure and
roadway that's in disrepair. Um example
number five shows some that if you
traveled in the area, you probably have
definitely noticed. Number five is Route
8 between Sam's Club and um
Michael's.
No, this yeah.
Between
Yes, it's I believe it's right uh
there actually behind the the Cheyenne
Vision Clinic.
Uh there's areas where the curb and
gutter systems are completely
gone. They've almost completely returned
to the earth. So, they are they're
failing.
Um that that's affecting drainage,
pedestrian connectivity, Converse. Um
that's number five. Uh that area, the
roadway is has been substandard for
years and it is
uh quickly deteriorating. There's lots
of ruts in it, bumps. It's it's a little
bit of a bumpy ride. Uh the city
engineer has identified the bridge shown
in number five. This is a
a structure that needs replacement
because it is um nearing the end of its
lifespan. Uh they're looking to have a
project in the near future to
rehabilitate Converse and that bridge.
Um so, those are uh examples of
of infrastructure that is in disrepair
um and uh deteriorating out there.
Um something that's also surprising is
just the predominance of flood
flood-prone properties in this area,
specifically around Del Range. A lot of
work has been done in the past since the
flood of 1985 to channelize and create
areas for water to go during flood
events, but there still are some areas
uh predominantly south of
the shopping center uh where you do have
flood plain uh
lands where they're in the 100-year
flood plain or in the 500-year flood
plain.
Um a lot of this does lend itself to
increased cost for development, but also
increased cost for
uh
operating a business there because you
may have to have or you may need to have
uh flood insurance.
So again, the Del Rio District, there
are numerous
uh blight conditions that we observed
and have documented.
The Yellowstone District, this is uh up
north. This is
based generally located in the area of
Western Hills, Story Boulevard, and
Yellowstone Road.
Uh we looked at a couple of
of different um areas where there are uh
concerns with with with blight. Uh the
area which is Element Church, uh there's
areas there where you have uh sidewalks
that aren't continuous.
You have issues with curb, gutter,
sidewalk, uh those types of items
deteriorating. We do have some flood
issues at Yellowstone uh Road. The
Subway
store is actually located within a
100-year flood plain. Um and there's
some other businesses out there that are
affected by the flood plain.
Um there also are some examples of
issues when it comes to street
connectivity uh for vehicles and
pedestrians. A lot of this is due to the
multiple jurisdictional agencies that
had to review things back in the day.
You know, you had the DOT uh with heavy
influence on Yellowstone Road regarding
um access cuz it's a state highway. You
had some county pockets up there in the
past and uh different review agencies
allowing for different things to happen.
Um example number two you there.
Uh this is an example of a defective uh
street layout. This is a portion of
Miller Lane where I is a half street. Um
at sometime a portion of Miller Lane
was uh abandoned and was
uh brought over to this one property
owner and it presently exists that way
right now even with new development
occurring mainly to the north, which is
creating some issues with connectivity.
East Lincoln Way, uh this is an area
where we are
hoping to see some additional
redevelopment occur in upcoming uh
months.
Uh there are a lot of uh different
issues you can see out that direction
and we just highlighted a few of these.
Um one of them is a dilapidated uh and
abandoned and deteriorating structure.
This is the Wyoprints Motors, which is
located on Lincoln Way near uh the
former
Midas shop, now Nick's Garage, I
believe.
Uh that is an example of a deteriorating
building um in the neighborhood. It was
probably predominantly uh developed in
the
50s and 60s. There's a lot of uh
drainage issues and uh concerns out
there where you have uh
incomplete alley approaches. They've
deteriorated. You have drainage
concerns. You just have general road
deterioration
um as well.
South Cheyenne, another um area of town
that was looked at for the first town
for the first time.
Uh there are uh concerns with the
multi-jurisdictional elements that have
that been in this area where you have
city development and county development.
I would like to note that I did not show
city limits in any of these maps and the
reason we didn't show city limits was
because of the
um
the fact that our goal is to allow this
to incorporate other sections when
things are annexed, but they didn't want
folks to look at the overall picture and
feel like they were limited to certain
areas of the community or this was just
a certain area of
of blight.
But here we're looking at yes.
>> one comment question too is like even
looking back to kind of the Yellowstone
area, there's a lot of county pockets
that are in there
as well, right?
>> Um
for you
President to Mr. Whitehead the county
pockets up north have all been taken
care of. We are actually on our final
round of county pocket annexations.
>> Okay.
>> The final county pocket annexation
package will be introduced on
February 9th on Monday and it should
wrap up by March 9th.
>> Okay.
>> we will have all county pockets
complete.
>> That's a good point. Thank you.
>> So and I I would like to note that our
goal would be to
have this go in front of the governing
body
after that annexation is complete so we
could make sure we capture those county
pockets
since they're pending in this this
blight designation.
This area South Cheyenne has a lot of
different issues because you had a lot
of different subdivisions that have
occurred in the city and the county.
And there's a lot of topography that
some limitations. Example number two is
Cribbon Avenue to York Avenue. There's a
large hill there south of South High
School which has proven to be
problematic
as a connection to the south. So that's
that's a
an example of a defective or inadequate
street layout. There's other areas that
haven't been identified in the in this
area. For example, one
that is there would be Allison Road
connection to Parsley Boulevard. We
didn't highlight that one, but
Allison Road is just one half block from
connecting between Parsley all the way
to college.
Um it's
really two houses that stand in the way
of making a major east-west road, which
has its pros and it has its cons.
Um there's also examples of pedestrian
connectivity misses. For example, number
two at the top left is the pedestrian
multi-use path on the Parsley
uh street bridge over Interstate 80.
It's presently lacking
uh connections to the neighborhood um to
the north. Um however, we're actually
working on a contract to uh make that
connection happen. At this time today,
it's still um identified as um
inadequate street uh layout because it
doesn't provide that pedestrian
connection.
Um and as you move north into the uh
southside neighborhood, uh we still do
have properties that are within
floodways and floodplains that are not
under the ownership of the city. Um
majority of them are, but a lot but some
of them are not.
>> Uh Chair 3, you have a question for Mr.
Bloomen
maybe touching on, you know, an earlier
comment uh you made
uh regarding the city versus the county
uh
li- limits not being shown on the maps.
But I had a question for both South
Cheyenne and um the park Swan Ranch.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
Are are are these blight areas going
east
all the way through the city bro- the
inside the city? There's there's nothing
east that's being excluded.
>> Mr. 32 Commissioner Board Member Duggan.
Yes, the intent is it would expand to
the entirety of the city
and
the vision and the the goals of urban
renewal are
even if you have if you have
reinvestment in one area of the
community, it still does serve and have
a relationship with other areas. For
example, we recently approved the Bell
Building plan and project.
You know, there wasn't a a crystal clear
designation of blight for that one
specific parcel of land. However,
taking that property and improving it is
going to have a domino effect and and
spread and those effects will be felt
along the other areas of
of the areas designated blight.
With this particular study, we're still
just looking for examples that
that show
blight in different areas and there are
definitely examples that are located
further to the southeast of
I'm in that part of the community.
So, those areas would still be eligible
for future plans and projects.
>> So, for clarification though,
we are not extending
the the the blight survey for both Swan
Ranch and South Cheyenne aren't
incorporating
isn't incorporating all of the city
proper east. I'm not sure where the
city-county boundary is.
South Cheyenne and Swan Ranch, I don't
know for South Cheyenne would that be
um
College Drive? I don't know.
>> Mr. 32 Commissioner Duggan, the intent
would be to expand the blight
designation to the entirety of the city
limits. So, it would include the area
Swan Ranch. It would include, for
example, the Sweet Grass area, the Camp
Stover Road area of the city.
and we didn't uh include this, but we'll
also include, you know, the areas
extending to the south,
uh which would be towards Bison Business
Park and the High Plains Business Park.
>> Okay, thank you.
>> So, in the um in the study,
uh we
it's about 102 pa- 100 pages of a study.
Um there are append- appendices in here.
Um the first append- append- uh appendix
has the blight surveys, which have been
updated uh to include the new areas, and
then the remainder of the appendix B has
uh different photos that uh were
observed, you know, situations and and
happenings that were observed in these
study areas.
Um not all of those were translated to
the map, but so there are more areas
shown in the
uh appendix.
So, staff is recommending approval of
this item.
Um and just for clarification, we wanted
to
note that any expansion of the city
limits in the future will require an
amendment to the study, and our goal
would be to include
that amendment um as additional append-
appendices as they come in.
So, we'll just add add them in at the
end.
And probably for good clarification, um
it would probably be a good to place in
the motion
that you all recognize the uh present
pending county pocket annexation action
that we have going on right now,
and that uh this
blight study incorporate
uh uh or be presented to the governing
body after annexation is complete to
incorporate those county pockets.
So, I'm open for any questions. I know
this is a pretty um high-level just
just uh touched on the the top
um presentation. If you have any more
questions, I'm welcome to answer those.
>> Okay.
I can't see everybody. Um so I don't I
can't see if anybody has a hand raisers
has questions.
Okay, there you guys are.
Okay. Uh
then do we have a motion?
>> Microphone.
Uh this is John Brody. I'm the city
attorney here in Cheyenne. Um I just
wanted to talk with the board a little
bit. This idea of citywide designation
is a novel use of your urban renewal
authority.
Um it is not clearly contemplated in the
statutes.
Um and there are due process
considerations that you should take into
consideration. There's specific
findings, obviously, that you have to
make when it comes to conditions of
blight.
Um and I just I I'm not saying that this
isn't appropriate, but I just want you
to understand that this is a a novel way
to use the urban renewal authority.
And that um
I guess the more specific and
comprehensive findings you have included
um within that designation, um the
better off you'd be to challenge if
someone were to take issue with uh this
use of urban renewal authority.
So, I just wanted to offer that.
>> Thank you, Mr. Brody. Charles, I can't
see is there anyone else with comments?
>> Chair, we do not have anyone else with
comments.
>> Got it. Okay.
Do I have a motion?
>> And chair, before your motion, echoing
what Mr. Brody said,
um would probably be advantageous for us
to
uh have a reference that
the blight study does illustrate
multiple conditions of blight in the
city.
Um you all can
take it to whatever level you want,
which is just to say as illustrated in
the the blight report, or if you wanted,
you could sort of go one by one and say
conditions 1 2 5 7 9.
Um so it would be your choice as to how
you would reference that it meets the
findings for blight designation.
Sorry, that means you're going to almost
have to write your own motion on the
dais.
>> Chair, through you. So Charles,
basically what what you're telling us is
um we're looking
to make this motion and add a few things
which would include
um
a reference to the county pockets
currently in process of annexation
and that we would also need to
um
have clear
conditions of blight
to um
get this approved. I guess my question
is
what does that second part of the motion
look like, or what should it look like?
>> And chair, members of the board, to
board member Graham,
um that reference to meeting the
conditions of blight could be as as high
level as saying that meets multiple
conditions of blight as illustrated in
the blight study.
Great.
>> Okay, I'll give it a stab since everyone
else was quiet.
Um, I'll make a motion
uh, to move to recommend the governing
body to approve the updated blight study
applied to the entire of the city limits
noting that any expansion of city limits
in the future will require an amendment
to this study.
And I also want to make reference to
the county pockets that are currently
going through the annexation process
and that all conditions of blight need
to be notated in the in the blight
study.
>> I will second that motion.
>> Great.
>> Any further discussion on the motion?
Okay, we will take a vote. All those in
favor? I.
>> I.
>> Okay, approved.
The next item on the agenda I think is
other business.
Do we have any other business?
>> Chair members of the board, I would just
like to note a couple of different items
as these are more housekeeping items
that
um, are going through is
we have been working with the developer
of the
Bell building which is the recent plan
and project you all approved. Um,
they've been going through the DOT with
their access permit.
Uh, the previous developer had indicated
that
they were only going to have about seven
to eight parking spaces and then this
new proposal was a pretty significant
increase.
So, initially their access request was
denied by the DOT, which is common for
to be denied, and then it's required to
go to an appeal board for a next
decision. Sometimes it gets appealed,
it's withheld, sometimes it's upheld,
sometimes it's reversed.
Um in this case, there were some
concerns with
how the
traffic would enter and exit, and it
would result in a lot of different
changes to the structure,
um like addition of another garage,
changing a lot of the facade that was
just recently redone.
Um so, the owner has indicated that they
are going to be looking at taking that
back to the previous concept, which
would be
not the
pigeonhole parking, if you will, the
elevator parking, but it would have more
residential units, storefronts, and such
in there. So,
they're going to continue to evaluate
that. Um so, we're going to work with
them on
um
bringing that through the urban renewal
process.
Everything they're doing right now does
still fall into the
uh approved and authorized activities on
the plan and project. So, they will do
their TIF application, but they will
also be providing clarification as to
how this project has changed.
So, that is I'm going to continue to be
done.
Um
secondly, do you have any any questions
on that?
Okay.
Uh
The next update is
in regard to
um tax increment financing payments.
Uh we recently
received payment for um
our areas
that are plans and projects right now,
and we actually were able to move into
the black for the Hitching Post, which
means the parcel that was the former
Hitching Post
uh development has generated an
increment. So, we were able to uh
essentially make our first payment to
the lender to satisfy uh that pledge
that we had put together that the
increment would go to them. That dollar
amount was to approximately $62,000.
Um this
this increment, unfortunately, is
performing uh behind um where it should
be, um but looking at projections for
how property tax will be collected and
what will occur with future um
development in the area, um we do see it
settling that um that debt, um but it's
not in the way that was envisioned by
everybody
um at the get-go.
Um the other item is the two um NJS
apartment developments, the one at Jolly
Roger and the one here um
at
just at O'Neal and 19th. Those continue
to move forward. I believe they were a
little bit delayed um because of some
issues that um be that started at the
beginning of the project, but those
continue to move forward. So, those are
um moving forward as planned. Um we're
hoping to see um what those increments
will look like, but we're not
anticipating any major issues there.
>> Uh
Chair, through you, I have a question
for Mr. Blumen in that regard. Uh what
is the anticipated
completion
occupation of those apartments?
>> And Chair, through you to comment to
board member Diggs, I do believe the
current opening for what's called West
End Flats, I believe that is now August
or September of this year.
Um it was originally supposed to be
around March or so.
Um and the air, that's the one that's
located out on US 30.
Um I believe it's shooting for the same
time. I'm not exactly sure, but I
believe it's right around the same time
for that project.
>> Have any other questions or any other
other business?
>> Um chair, I I do not have any other um
questions or
or any other updates for you all.
>> Cool.
>> I'll make a motion to adjourn if there's
no other questions chair for you. Yep.
>> I will second that motion and we'll take
a vote on it. All those in favors, I.
>> I.
>> Okay, meeting is adjourned.
>> All right, thank you.